Guide to the Lionel Wolberger papers, 1965-1993.
Wolberger, Lionel papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lionel Wolberger papers, 1965-1993.
4990
Wolberger, Lionel.
2.5 cubic ft.
Audio recordings, computer media, printed materials, correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, creative and academic writings, and musical work, including scores, sheet music, and programs and broadsides for musical performances; also, audiocassettes, phonodiscs,videotapes, and CDs and DVDs of digitized material.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Composer.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, creative and academic writings, and musical work, including scores, sheet music, and programs and broadsides for musical performances; also, audiocassettes, phonodiscs,videotapes, and CDs and DVDs of digitized material.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Wolberger, Lionel.
Subjects:
Composers -- United States.; Music -- Instruction and study.; Music -- Performance.; Composition (Music); Composers; Composition (Music); Music -- Instruction and study; Music -- Performance
Places:
United States
Form and Genre Terms:
Audio cassettes.; Videotapes.; Phonograph records.; Scores.; Sheet music.; Programs (documents).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Writing & Performance Materials
Box 1
Series II. Recordings
Boxes 1-3
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Writing & Performance Materials
  - Elementary / High School and early University Writings, 1969-1981 (Box 1)
    Poems, typed and hand-written, primarily from elementary school; a high school biology project; report cards; a high school graduation certificate; academic essays at the high school and undergraduate-level; song lyrics; a published poem in Praxis (Volume 4, Number 2); a blue-hued idea notebook (1978-1979); and an essay, titled "Universe Unfolding," marked by Wolberger.
  - Academic, Religious, and Musical Writings, 1981-1987 (Box 1)
    Musical notation; essays on the Torah and Judaism; poems; a copy of Wolberger's oral examination on ethnomusicology and Jewish music (1987); performance posters; and, a copy of Wolberger's MA thesis.
  - Professional, Dramatic, and Musical Writings, 1987-1996 (Box 1)
    Letters of recommendation from Yale University; a certificate of appreciation from the American Zionist Movement Zionist Song Competition; musical notation; draft copy of Love in the First Degree: a Musical in One Act; copy of Rainbow Warrior; musical notation and draft copy of The Enchanted; and, draft copy of Peace Cantata.
  - "Hoot Night" Set List, Song Introductions, Lyrics and Chords, Undated (Box 1)
    Green notebook; includes two programs.
  - Cyrus Zain: A Cubist Musical, 1985 (Box 1)
    Black notebook (bound); includes lyrics with accompanying chords.
  - Newspaper Clippings, Performance Fliers, and Miscellanea, 1975-1987 (Box 1)
    Loose and unfoldered
- Series II. Recordings
  - The Coop: The Fast Folk Musical Magazine, 1982-08; SR-15342-15344 (Box 1)
    Three copies; side two / song five: "Drawing the Map" by Lionel Wolberger; copies two and three include a copy of "The Coop" publication
    LP
  - Rainbow Warrior (Side 1), Undated; TR-11512 (Box 2)
    Ampex Precision Magnetic Tape
    Reel to reel
  - Rainbow Warrior (Side 2), Undated; TR-11513 (Box 2)
  - World of Jewis Music Concert / Lecture, 1993-11-15; TR-11514 (Box 2)
    JCAC, Omaha
    Cassettes
  - A: The Enchanted (Songs) / B: My Father's Wedding Day, 1990-03-25; TR-11515 (Box 2)
    A: "music + lyrics by Lee Peridot + Lionel Wolberger" / B: "by Lee Peridot"
  - Enchanted Live - Version #3 Part—A, Undated; TR-11516 (Box 2)
  - OPUS #1: Ilturim, 1991-01-02; TR-11517 (Box 2)
    "7: Tire l'aiguille (Em) / 8: Ne me quitte pas (Am)"
  - Hoot Night / Rhodes, Casio, Echo, 1982-10-11; TR-11518 (Box 2)
  - Rainbow Warrior - Dub from Video, 1986; TR-11519 (Box 2)
    Track listing included
  - Cyrus Zain Master Rehearsal, 1985-12-11; TR-11520 (Box 2)
  - Hoot Night - Tyson's Studio (Sat.), 1983-05-28; TR-11521 (Box 2)
  - Hoot Night - Tyson's Studio (Fri.), 1983-05-27; TR-11522 (Box 2)
  - Enchanted Live - Version #3 Part—B, Undated; TR-11523 (Box 2)
  - Love in the First Degree Reading @ MTC (Part 3), 1988-05-28; TR-11524 (Box 2)
  - Love in the First Degree Reading @ MTC (Part 1 and 2), 1988-05-28; TR-11525 (Box 2)
  - Love in the 1st Degree, 1988-05-28; TR-11526 (Box 2)
  - Song Tape, 1988-08-23; TR-11527 (Box 2)
    Miriam Hoffman address included
  - Rudy's Jukebox - Who's Rudy?, 1989; TR-11528 (Box 2)
  - The Wind Blows In (Master), 1983-06-16; TR-11529 (Box 2)
    Starring Roger Lawson and Cheryl Politzer
  - Tammany II, 1983-11-12; TR-11530 (Box 2)
  - Tammanny / The Wind Blows In (Mixed), 1983-11-12; TR-11531 (Box 2)
  - Tammany, 1983-02-24; TR-11532 (Box 2)
  - Gig: Li-Rk-Jz, 1983-03-01; TR-11533 (Box 2)
  - Set for Speak Disco, 1982-10-19; TR-11534 (Box 2)
  - Speakeasy Gig / Cheryl + Lionel - 1st Trax, 1982-02-02, 1982-12-13; TR-11535 (Box 2)
  - Improvisation @ ZCH w/ Jonathan Miller, 1990-10-21; TR-11536 (Box 2)
  - Final Cuts: Bardstown Lighting / But For You, Undated; TR-11537 (Box 2)
  - Tammany / Green Room, 1981-04-29, 1981-05-08; TR-11538 (Box 2)
  - Rehearsal for Gig: Limbo, Undated; TR-11539 (Box 2)
  - Tape for Brian Miller - Solo Piano, Undated; TR-11540 (Box 2)
  - The Messengers Rehearsal @ CBGB, 1981-08-30; TR-11541 (Box 2)
  - Better Music Thru Science at Commons (Reel I), Undated; TR-11542 (Box 2)
    Reel to reel (35-90)
  - Better Music Thru Science at Commons (Reel II), Undated; TR-11543 (Box 2)
  - Business Card Optical Scan, Undated; CD-3266 (Box 2)
    Includes a copy of the eponymous business card
    CD
  - Live WVBR Concert at the Commons Coffee House, Ithaca, NY (Disc 1), 1980; CD-3267 (Box 2)
    This recording is an imperfect digitized copy of the reel to reel recording (TR-11542)
  - Live WVBR Concert at the Commons Coffee House, Ithaca, NY (Disc 2), 1980; CD-3268 (Box 2)
    This recording is an imperfect digitized copy of the reel to reel recording (TR-11543)
  - The Haunt, Ithaca, NY, 1980-01-22; DVD-1995 (Box 2)
    This recording is an imperfect digitized copy of the VHS recording (V-9676)
    DVD
  - Noyes Pub, Cornell University, 1980-04-26; DVD-1996 (Box 2)
    This recording is an imperfect digitized copy of the VHS recording (V-9675)
  - Shulamit, 1984-08; V-9669 (Box 2)
    VHS
  - Fall of Stiltsville Master, 1992-05; V-9670 (Box 2)
  - Dante's Ovine Comedy: Selected Scenes, Undated; V-9671 (Box 2)
    Hawley/Wolberger
  - BMTS - Ten Year Anniversary, 1980-01-22, 1980-04-26, 1980-05-09; V-9672 (Box 2)
    The Haunt, Noyes Pub, Public Access
  - Three Little Piano Songs, 1983-05-10; V-9673 (Box 2)
    Credits included on back
  - Dr. Klezmer at Borders Books / Hebrew Class @ United Talmud Torah, 1996-05; V-9674 (Box 2)
    Omaha
  - Better Music Thru Science Video 'Intakes', 1980-04-26, 1980-05-09; V-9675 (Box 2)
    Noyes Pub and GATV; camerawork by Nash Bly
  - Better Music Thru Science at the Haunt, 1980-01-22; V-9676 (Box 2)
  - Better Music Thru Science at the Haunt, 1980-01-22; V-9677 (Box 2)
    U-Matic
  - Better Music Thru Science: 1980 / Hiroshima / GATV Documentaries / Edited Songs (Also - Josh Fried), 1980; V-9678 (Box 2)
  - Dance version of Come Together, Undated; TR-11413 (Box 3)
    15 IPS, two-track stereo, DBX
  - Music Library (Composed and Performed by Lionel Wolberger), Undated; TR-11414 (Box 3)
  - "Just noisy kids.", 1970; TR-11415 (Box 3)
    "Very old. 1970? / Just noisy kids. / Family keepsake / Lionel Wolberger"
  - Songs Tame and Wild (Tape 1), Undated; TR-11416 (Box 3)
    7 1/2 IPS, 1/4 track, track listing included; Lionel Wolberger on vocals and piano
  - Songs Tame and Wild (Tape 2), Undated; TR-11417 (Box 3)
    7 1/2 IPS, 1/4 track, track listing included; Lionel Wolberger on piano
  - Come Together, 1980; TR-11418 (Box 3)
  - Stacia Dance (Dance 2), Undated; TR-11419 (Box 3)
    7 1/2 IPS
  - Projectape Music 460, Undated; TR-11420 (Box 3)
    Track listing on inside of box
  - Green Room Various Songs, 1981-04-29; TR-11421 (Box 3)
    Track listing on back of box
  - Good 36 (#3), 1981-04-29; TR-11422 (Box 3)
  - Tammany #2, 1981-05-08; TR-11423 (Box 3)
  - Tammany #1, 1981-05-08; TR-11424 (Box 3)
  - "(Arts Week, Arts Week) It's Time for Arts Week", 1986; TR-11425 (Box 3)
    7 1/2 IPS, 1/2 track, Mono
  - Bright and Sunny Master, Undated; TR-11426 (Box 3)
  - Scenes from Hamlet, Undated; TR-11427 (Box 3)
  - Music 460 Projectape 2, Undated; TR-11428 (Box 3)
    Track listing on front of box
  - #11 Yom Kippur / Shaare Zion, Sioux City, 1993-09-25; TR-11429 (Box 3)
  - (#3) R. Hash / Ana - Morning, 1993-09-16; TR-11430 (Box 3)
  - #8 Kolnidre, 1993-09-24; TR-11431 (Box 3)
  - #10 Yom Kippur / Shaare Zion, Sioux City, 1993-09-25; TR-11432 (Box 3)
  - #9 Kolnidre / Shaare Zion, 1993-09-24; TR-11433 (Box 3)
  - #7 2nd Evening / Rosh Hashanah/ Shaare Zion - Sioux City, IA, 1993-09-17; TR-11434 (Box 3)
  - BMTS, Undated; TR-11435 (Box 3)
  - Eretz Tropit -- Poory -- Lionel / Better Music Thru Science, Undated; TR-11436 (Box 3)
  - Direct Recording of Kurzwell x Alesis, 1990-05-20; TR-11437 (Box 3)
    BBYO @ Beth Israel, New Haven
  - BMTS at Risley, 1982-04-24; TR-11438 (Box 3)
  - BMTS at the Haunt, Undated; TR-11439 (Box 3)
  - BMTS >> Nite Court, Undated; TR-11440 (Box 3)
  - Wednesday Eve - R. Hashana #1, 1990-09-15; TR-11441 (Box 3)
  - #5 1st Morning / Rosh Hashanah / Shaare Zion Syn., Sioux City, 1993-09-16; TR-11442 (Box 3)
  - #13 Last Yom Kippur Tape / Shaare Zion / Sioux City, 1993-09-25; TR-11443 (Box 3)
  - H. Holiday, Undated; TR-11444 (Box 3)
  - Cantorial Master Tape, 1992; TR-11445 (Box 3)
  - Kedushash, Hashkivenu, Simshalom, Undated; TR-11446 (Box 3)
  - #12 Yom Kippur / Shaare Zion / Sioux City, 1993-09-25; TR-11447 (Box 3)
  - (#3) R. Hashana - Morning, 1973-09-16; TR-11448 (Box 3)
  - #6 2nd Day / Rosh Hashanah / Shaare Zion - Sioux City, 1993-09-17; TR-11449 (Box 3)
  - Ramah Mix - Lio, Peh, Ellen, 1983-07-22; TR-11450 (Box 3)
  - Songs Tame and Wild, 1983; TR-11451 (Box 3)
  - Songs Tame and Wild (Master Copy), 1983; TR-11452 (Box 3)
  - Paul Sutherland Dance (Who Stole the Moon?), Undated; TR-11453 (Box 3)
  - Tape Backup / Alesis, 1989; TR-11454 (Box 3)
  - Letter from Israel, Undated; TR-11455 (Box 3)
  - Mom's Answering Tape, 1985; TR-11456 (Box 3)
  - Purim, 1986; TR-11457 (Box 3)
    Ellen / Jay / Karen / Lionel / Perry
  - Pooreem Goodbye, 1988-03-05; TR-11458 (Box 3)
  - Gig: Wiseman - Aryeh, Yossi, Steve (Tape 1), 1990-04-01; TR-11459 (Box 3)
    Avruhum Wiseman Wedding
  - Gig: Wiseman - Aryeh, Yossi, Steve (Tape 2), Undated; TR-11460 (Box 3)
  - Gig: Purim Bikur Kholim - Aryeh, Yossi, Steve, 1990-03-10; TR-11461 (Box 3)
  - Healing Music - Places Songs for Ellen Rubin, 1989-04-07; TR-11462 (Box 3)
    Jake, Frank, Lionel
  - Klezmer Connection at Thomas Sweet, 1989-12-15; TR-11463 (Box 3)
  - MIDI 2, 1989-04-01; TR-11464 (Box 3)
  - Ivy Room, Undated; TR-11465 (Box 3)
  - Limitations - Interview Segment, 1980-04-17; TR-11466 (Box 3)
  - Songs Old Played, 1980-05-19; TR-11467 (Box 3)
  - Rav Lincoln Center / Dream ADD, 1982-01; TR-11468 (Box 3)
  - Playing Poems / GOD - (conc), Undated; TR-11469 (Box 3)
  - Mom Shopping - Piano Songs (1 and 2), 1982-02-03, 1982-03-15, 1982-03-24; TR-11470 (Box 3)
  - Crickets - Lio and Josh - Dishwasher Safe, Undated; TR-11471 (Box 3)
  - Casio - Van to Philly - Philly Mall, 1982-05-11; TR-11472 (Box 3)
  - Casio / Wash. Sq., 1982-05-20; TR-11473 (Box 3)
  - Casio - Wakeman Journey, 1982-05-05; TR-11474 (Box 3)
  - Songtape / Experimenting with 5/5 Tape / Streets, Forest Hills, Ramah, 1982-04-17, 1982-11-22; TR-11475 (Box 3)
  - Songtape Early / Cheryl Sessions, Berkley Songs, Forest Hills (#2), 1982-12-17, 1983; TR-11476 (Box 3)
  - ADD - Naomi and Daphne, Undated; TR-11477 (Box 3)
  - Phone Book - MIDI, Undated; TR-11478 (Box 3)
  - Play - Sabbatai Sevi, Undated; TR-11479 (Box 3)
  - NWVB - Big Red Barn / Man ORK / Laundry Room, 1980; TR-11480 (Box 3)
  - M. Steven Brooks - Piano, Undated; TR-11481 (Box 3)
  - Katherine Kollar 1st Night, Undated; TR-11482 (Box 3)
  - "Bali" by John Miller, 1990-02; TR-11483 (Box 3)
    Organ by Lionel Wolberger, Tel Aviv
  - Musical Jerusalem - Ratisbonne, 1991-06-06; TR-11484 (Box 3)
  - Klezmer Konnection Demo Tape - Cantorial Demo Tape, 1992-01-04; TR-11485 (Box 3)
  - Julie's: Wheatfield / Ballet Class: @ ECA, 1991-12, 1992-02-07; TR-11486 (Box 3)
  - Torah Chant at Friedel, 1993-12-03; TR-11487 (Box 3)
    Genesis 12, 2nd and 3rd
  - Peace Cantata Rehearsal, 1991-08; TR-11488 (Box 3)
  - Genesis 31 Kids Chant / Omaha, 1996-05; TR-11489 (Box 3)
    Partial recording
  - Scud Attack, 1991-01; TR-11490 (Box 3)
  - OPUS #2: Ilturim, 1991-01-11; TR-11491 (Box 3)
  - Play: West Side Story, 1982-07; TR-11492 (Box 3)
  - Demo BMTS, Undated; TR-11493 (Box 3)
  - Better Music Thru Science, Too, Undated; TR-11494 (Box 3)
  - Rocket Launch, 1972; TR-11495 (Box 3)
    Robert and Lionel Berger at Flushing Meadow Park
  - Miscellaneous, Undated; TR-11496 (Box 3)
  - Bar Mitzvah Tape, Undated; TR-11497 (Box 3)
  - Songs Assorted, 1973-1975; TR-11498 (Box 3)
  - Cat Synthesizer with Josh Zieman, 1978; TR-11499 (Box 3)
  - Music Tape G: Kosson Comedy - Composing Music Room - Tammany!, 1978-1979; TR-11500 (Box 3)
  - The Hagaddah, 1983-08-15; TR-11501 (Box 3)
    Solelim Play
  - Songs 1st Spiral (Blue), TR-11502 (Box 3)
  - Tape Music, Undated; TR-11503 (Box 3)
  - Beatlegs Primal Screams, Undated; TR-11504 (Box 3)
  - Cyn, Lio, Peh / Improv for Brian, Undated; TR-11505 (Box 3)
  - Gig: Holocaust Surv. Hanukah, 1990; TR-11506 (Box 3)
    New Haven
  - Camp Naomi Songfest, 1979; TR-11507 (Box 3)
  - Camp Naomi Songfest, 1980; TR-11508 (Box 3)
  - Moon Lite, Undated; TR-11509 (Box 3)
  - Friedel Jewish Academy Presents … Yehuda & The Young Maccabees, 1993-12-15; V-9666 (Box 3)
    At JCC Theater, (1:07:16)
  - The Greeks, 1992-04-03; V-9667 (Box 3)
  - Oddfellows' Peace Cantata, 1991-11-16; V-9668 (Box 3)